Finding Aid for Office of the Vice President for Research (University of Michigan), Records, 1950-2001
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
- Presidential Initiatives Fund (PIF), 1986-1999
  - OVPR Grant Administration, 1986-1999
    - PIF Proposal Submissions
      - Proposals 1-30, 1987-1988; 30 folders (Box 173)
      - Proposals 31-43, 1987-1988; 13 folders (Box 174)
      - Pre-Proposals 1-82, 1988-1989; 82 folders (Box 174)
      - Pre-Proposals 83-105, 1988-1989; 23 folders (Box 175)
      - Final Proposals, 1988-1989; 2 folders (Box 175)
      - Proposal Binder, 1994-1995 (Box 175)
      - Proposal Binder, 1996-1997 (Box 175)
    - Reviews
      - Reviews of Proposals 1-30, 1986-1987; 3 folders (Box 175)
      - Reviews of Proposals 31-145, 1986-1987; 12 folders (Box 176)
      - Deans and Directors Comments, 1986-1987 (Box 176)
      - Reviews of Proposals 1-43, 1987-1988; 4 folders (Box 176)
      - Deans and Directors Comments, 1987-1988 (Box 176)
      - Reviews of Final Proposals (24 folders for reviewers numbered 1-24), 1988-1989 (Box 177)
      - Proposal Review Comments and Ranking, 1994-1995 (Box 177)
      - Proposal Reviews, 1996-1997 (Box 177)
    - Budgets and Financial
      - Budgets, 1986-1989; 3 folders (Box 177)
      - Accounting, 1991-1994 (Box 177)
    - Reports from Projects, circa 1988-1991; 3 folders (Box 177)
      (Reports to OVPR)
    - Reports from Projects, circa 1992-1995; 3 folders (Box 177)
    - Miscellaneous OVPR PIF Files
      - Awards-to-Date Listing, February 1999 (Box 177)
      - Clinical Trials Proposal, 1987 (Box 177)
      - Kellogg Grant Publications and Press, 1987-1989 (Box 177)
      - Round 1 Awardees' Luncheon, March 1988 (Box 177)
      - Symposium"Reflections on the First Two Years", 1988-1989 (Box 177)
  - Project Files (Box 178)
    - A-K (Box 178)
      (More or less)
    - L-Z (Box 179)
- Contractual Restrictions Requests (PAF-R's), 1987-2005
  - PAF-R's
    The Contractual Restrictions Requests (PAF_R's), 1987-2005 series consists of "Request for Approval for Contractual Restrictions on Research." (The forms are now known as PAF-R's, and were previously known as 7679R's). The requests are organized according to fiscal year. Many of the requests concern classified research. Also included in this series are copies of Regental Research Policies. These policies outline how the University engages in classified research, and under what circumstances. The files titled "Volakis" contain materials on a dispute between the University and the United States Air Force concerning restrictions the Air Force wanted to place on a research contract with the University. The project under dispute was led by UM Professor John L. Volakis. Researchers should also consult the Classified and Controversial Research, 1971-1999 sub-series for further materials on classified research projects and policies.
    - 1987-1988, 2 folders (Box 213)
    - 1988-1989, 2 folders (Box 213)
    - 1989-1990, 2 folders (Box 213)
    - 1990-1991
      - Folders 1-2 of 6 (Box 213)
      - Folders 3-6 of 6 (Box 214)
    - 1991-1992, 3 folders (Box 214)
    - 1992-1993 (Box 214)
    - 1993-1994, 2 folders (Box 214)
    - 1994-1995 (Box 214)
    - 1995-1996 (Box 214)
    - 1996-1997, 2 folders (Box 214)
    - 1997-1998 (Box 215)
    - 1998-1999 (Box 215)
    - 1999-2000 (Box 215)
    - 2000-2001, 2 folders (Box 215)
    - 2001-2002, 3 folders (Box 215)
    - 2002-2003, 2 folders (Box 215)
    - 2003-2004, 4 folders (Box 215)
    - 2004-2005, 3 folders (Box 216)
  - PAF-R's: Miscellaneous, 1991-1996 (Box 216)
  - Regental Research Policy
    - Miscellaneous, 1989 (Box 216)
    - Summaries, 1988-2002 (Box 216)
  - Report to the Regents, 1989 (Box 216)
  - Volakis, 1988-1990; 2 folders (Box 216)
- Michigan Life Sciences Corridor
  The Michigan Life Sciences Corriidor (MLSC) series focuses on the MLSC, an initiative in biotechnology that invests in biotech research at the University of Michigan (UM), Michigan State University (MSU), Wayne State University (WSU), and the VanAndel Institute in Grand Rapids. This series is made up of three sub-series: General Files; Core Technology Alliance (CTA); and the Michigan Life Sciences Corridor Fund (MLSC Fund; MLSCF).
  The General Files sub-series is the smallest of the three sub-series, and contains budget and miscellaneous materials related to the business and functions of the MLSC. This sub-series also contains some correspondence, and Steering Committee meeting materials.
  The Core Technology Alliance (CTA), 2000-2006 sub-series contains materials on the CTA Corporation. "The CTA Corporation is a not-for-profit non-stock membership organization owned equally by founding members Michigan State University (MSU), the University of Michigan (UM), Wayne State University (WSU), and the VanAndel Research Institute as well as non-founding members Western Michigan University (WMU), Kalamazoo Valley Community College, and Grand Valley State University (GVSU). It enables coordinated scientific leadership, marketing, strategic planning, and decision-making across the core facilities (http://www.ctaalliance.org)." The sub-series includes Board of Directors meeting materials, a long run of Executive Committee meeting materials, and correspondence. It also includes reports and studies such as Progress Reports, and the Anderson Economic Impact Study.
  The Michigan Life Sciences Corridor Fund (MLSC Fund; MLSCF), 2000-2002 sub-series primarily consists of a proposal entitled "Infrastructure for the Michigan Life Sciences Corridor." The proposal is divided into eleven sections and an appendix, and includes material on the organization of various centers and consortiums included in the MLSC. Also included are a presentation to Interim President B. Joseph White, and requests for proposals (RFP's).
  - General Files, 1999-2003
    - Biosciences Research and Commercialization Center (BRCC), Western Michigan University (WMU) -- Business Plan, September 15, 2003 (Box 216)
    - Core Technologies Proposal Budget Meeting, January 8, 2001 (Box 216)
    - Infrastructure Proposal and Budget Proposals, 2001 (Box 216)
    - Presentation by Robert Todd (Steering Committee Meeting), November 28, 2000 (Box 216)
    - Technical Advisory Committee Correspondence, 1999-2002 (Box 216)
  - Core Technology Alliance (CTA), 2000-2006
    - General, 2004-2006 (Box 216)
    - Anderson Economic Impact Study, January 23, 2004 (Box 216)
    - Annual Meeting, March 23, 2005 (Box 216)
    - Beamline (LS-CAT, DND-CAT), 2000-2002 (Box 216)
    - Biotechnology Symposium, May 14, 2002 (Box 216)
    - Board of Directors Meetings
      - May 4, 2004 (Box 216)
      - June 10, 2004 (Box 216)
      - July 13, 2004
        - General Meeting (Box 216)
        - Meeting with Core Facility Hub and Node Directors (Box 216)
      - September 30, 2004 (Box 216)
      - November 22, 2004 (Box 216)
      - January 13, 2005 (Box 216)
      - September 22, 2005 (Box 216)
      - November 29, 2005 (Box 216)
    - Briefing, President Mary Sue Coleman, August 19, 2002 (Box 217)
    - CTA Corporation Correspondence, 2003-2004 (Box 217)
    - Core Visit Itinerary, Feburary, 2004 (Box 217)
    - Correspondence
      - 2001 (Box 217)
      - 2002 (Box 217)
      - 2003 (Box 217)
      - 2004 (Box 217)
    - Dow Presentation, December 17, 2002 (Box 217)
    - Executive Committee Meetings
      - January 15, 2001 (Box 217)
      - February 14, 2001 (Box 217)
      - May 7, 2001 (Box 217)
      - June 12, 2001 (Box 217)
      - July 31, 2001 (Box 217)
      - August 30, 2001 (Box 217)
      - October 9, 2001 (Box 217)
      - November 1, 2001 (Box 217)
      - December 6, 2001 (Box 217)
      - January 18, 2002 (Box 217)
      - February 21, 2002 (Box 217)
      - March 28, 2002 (Box 217)
      - April 25, 2002 (Box 217)
      - June 19, 2002 (Box 217)
      - July 31, 2002 (Box 217)
      - August 23, 2002 (Box 217)
      - September 30, 2002 (Box 217)
      - October 25, 2002 (Box 217)
      - January 17, 2003 (Box 217)
      - March 28, 2003 (Box 217)
      - May 30, 2003 (Box 217)
      - June 25, 2003 (Box 217)
      - July 21, 2003 (Box 217)
      - August 28, 2003 (Box 217)
      - October 22, 2003 (Box 217)
      - November 7, 2003 (Box 217)
      - January 12, 2004 (Box 217)
      - February 20, 2004 (Box 217)
    - Executive Recruitment Meeting, November 22, 2004 (Box 217)
    - First Annual Meeting, March 24, 2004 (Box 217)
    - Michigan Center for Biological Information (MCBI)
      - General, 2001-2004 (Box 217)
      - Review, 2003-2004; 2 folders (Box 217)
    - Overview (of the CTA), 2003 (Box 217)
    - Progress Reports
      - April 2004, 2 folders (Box 217)
      - October 2004, 2 folders (Box 217)
      - October 2005, 3 folders (Box 218)
    - Retreat
      - February 23, 2001 (Box 218)
      - October 28, 2002 (Box 218)
    - Report to the MLSC Steering Committee, August 21, 2002 (Box 218)
    - Strategic Marketing Plan, December 2003 (Box 218)
  - Michigan Life Sciences Corridor Fund (MLSC Fund; MLSCF), 2000-2002
    - Presentation to Interim President B. Joseph White, January 2002 (Box 218)
    - Proposal: "Infrastructure for the Michigan Life Sciences Corridor,", June 23, 2002
      - Sections 1-6 (Box 218)
      - Section 7: Michigan Center for Genomic Technologies (Box 218)
      - Section 8: Michigan Proteome Consortium (Box 218)
      - Section 9: Michigan Center for Structural Biology (Box 218)
      - Section 10: Michigan Animal Model Consortium (Box 218)
      - Section 11: Michigan Center for Biological Information (MCBI) (Box 218)
      - Appendix (Box 218)
    - Request for Proposals (RFP) Draft, 2001-2002 (Box 218)
- Discretionary Fund, 1987-2000
  The Discretionary Fund, 1987-2000 series contains requests for funds from faculty, departments, and units. The sub-series are organized according to fiscal year, and the files within each sub-series are arranged alphabetically. The discretionary fund is managed by OVPR. Requests for funding include coverage of research expenses and equipment, publication subventions, conference attendance costs, performance expenses, and symposium/conference organization costs. Funding ranges from hundreds to hundreds-of-thousands of dollars.
  - 1987-1988
    - Aller, Hugh D. -- Goldstein, Irwin (Box 220)
    - Goldstein, Irwin -- Palsson, Bernard (Box 221)
    - Parsons, Jeffrey R. -- Zelenock, Gerald (Box 222)
  - 1988-1989
    - Adams, Julian -- Goad, Linda (Box 223)
    - Goldstein, Irwin -- Moody, David (Box 224)
    - Moore, Thomas -- West, Patrick (Box 225)
    - Weymouth, Terry -- Zolan, Miriam (Box 226)
  - 1989-1990
    - Abreu, Vincent -- Feldt, Allan (Box 226)
    - Feldt, Allan -- Mansfield, John (Box 227)
    - Marcelo, Cynthia -- Schelle, Hansjoerg (Box 228)
    - Schwartz, Jessica -- Zorn, Jens (Box 229)
  - 1990-1991
    - Abreu, Vincent -- Gruber, James (Box 230)
    - Gulari, Erdogan -- Midgley, A. Rees (Box 231)
    - Miller, Edwin -- Vandermeer, John (Box 232)
    - Warner, Robert -- Zirbes, Georgette (Box 233)
  - 1991-1992
    - Abreu, Vincent -- Crawford, David (Box 233)
    - Crowston, Kevin -- Kyes, Robert (Box 234)
    - Lakshmanan, Sridhar -- Shevoroshkin, Vitaly (Box 235)
    - Singer, David -- Zuidema, George (Box 236)
  - 1992-1993
    - Agranoff, Bernard -- Brophy, David (Box 236)
    - Brown, Susan -- Houk, Nancy (Box 237)
    - Humes, H. David -- Ramirez-Christensen, Esperanza (Box 238)
    - Raymond, Pamela -- Zuiderweg, Erik (Box 239)
  - 1993-1994
    - Adler, Ronald -- Gilchrist, Brian (Box 240)
    - Gilsdorf, Janet -- Molnar, Lawrence (Box 241)
    - Moore, David -- Stevenson, Harold (Box 242)
    - Stewart, Paul -- Zirbes, Georgette (Box 243)
  - 1994-1995
    - Adams, Barbara -- Bernstein, Dennis (Box 243)
    - Bernstein, Marc -- Gehring, William (Box 244)
    - Geisser, Michael -- Merlin, Roberto (Box 245)
    - Messick, Brinkley -- Sowers, Mary Fran (Box 246)
    - Sparling -- Peter -- Zucker, Roberto (Box 247)
  - 1995-1996
    - Adams, Julia -- Carlyon, David (Box 247)
    - Ceballo, Rosario -- Jackson, James (Box 248)
    - Jayaratne, Toby -- Nadelman, Lorraine (Box 249)
    - Nettles, Michael -- Vatsis, Kostas P. (Box 250)
    - Verbrugge, Lois -- Zirbes, Georgette (Box 251)
  - 1996-1997
    - Achen, Chris -- England, Anthony (Box 251)
    - Erickson, Steven -- Marino, Joseph (Box 252)
    - Marletta, Michael -- Singman, Jeffrey (Box 253)
    - Smith, Charles -- Zirbes, Georgette (Box 254)
  - 1997-1998
    - Alexander, William -- Chhibber, Pradeep (Box 254)
    - Chick, Steven -- Ma, Peter (Box 255)
    - Maio, Ronald -- Skelton, Logan (Box 256)
    - Smith, Yolanda -- Zurbuchen, Thomas (Box 257)
  - 1998-1999
    - Abriola, Linda -- Burrage, Mark (Box 257)
    - Burton, David -- Hunt, Alan (Box 258)
    - Hunt, Nancy -- Robins, Thomas (Box 259)
    - Root, Terry -- Zurier, Rebecca (Box 260)
  - 1999-2000
    - Abriola, Linda -- Gitlin, Scott (Box 261)
    - Glover, Thomas -- Nussbaum, Ronald (Box 262)
    - Nwankwo, Ifeoma -- Van Keeken, Peter (Box 263)
    - Velez-Aguayo, Evelyn -- Zucker, Robert (Box 264)
- Indirect Waivers, 1990-1996
  The Indirect Cost Waivers, 1990-1996 series is divided into two parts: Indirect Cost Waivers, and Indirect Cost Waivers (Former System). In each part the files are arranged alphabetically. The series consists of request for waivers of indirect costs related to various research projects. Some files also include copies of research proposals, research budgets, and correspondence regarding the requests.
  - Indirect Cost Waivers (Box 265)
    - Alliance for Minority Participation -- Zuidema, George (Box 265)
  - Indirect Cost Waivers (Former System)
    - Agranoff, B.W. -- Zuckerman, Howard (Box 265)
- Resaerch Faculty (RF) Appointments, 2007-2010
  The Research Faculty (RF) Appointments series includes materials on the appointment of research scientists at the university. The appointment could result from a new hire for the university, a transfer or sharing of an appointment between units within the university, or a promotion. Included in the files are CV's, recommendation letters, and correspondence. Each file also includes a letter approving the appointment from the vice president for research.
  - 2007 (Box 276)
    - Wilson, Michael (Box 276)
      [PR RESTRICTED until July 1, 2037 ]
  - 2008
    - Brescoll, Victoria (Box 276)
      [PR RESTRICTED until July 1 2038 ]
    - Fryxell, Bruce (Box 276)
    - Galecki, Andrzej (off-cycle RF promotion) (Box 276)
    - Hoard, John (Box 276)
    - Hu, Jingwen (Box 276)
    - Larsen-Freeman, Diane (Box 276)
    - McGonagle, Katherine (Box 276)
    - Myra, Eric (Box 276)
    - Page, Oliver A. (Box 276)
    - Reznicek, Anton A. (Box 276)
    - Salmeen, Irving T. (Box 276)
    - Sorensen, Roderick J. (Box 276)
    - Stephenson, David (Box 276)
    - Whaley, Arthur L. (Box 276)
  - 2009
    - Bynum, Timothy S. (Box 276)
      [PR RESTRICTED until July 1 2039 ]
    - Colpaert, Francis C. (Box 276)
    - Ghimire, Dhirga (Box 276)
    - Kovelman, Ioulia (Box 276)
    - Rosen, Hannah (Box 276)
    - Smith, John R. (Box 276)
  - 2010
    [PR RESTRICTED until July 1 2040 ]
    - Hassett, Afton L. (Box 276)
    - Landi, Enrico (Box 276)
    - Pietrykowski, Bruce (Box 276)
    - Shah, Prachi (Box 276)
    - Shalinsky, Mark (Box 276)